# **Syed Muhammad Ramees Alam**

♥ Karachi, Sindh, Pakistan ■ rameesalam96@gmail.com 🔲 0311-2575541 🌰 https://www.linkedin.com/in/rameesalam/

#### **SUMMARY**

I am an experienced Talent Acquisition Officer with a successful track record of identifying and recruiting top talent, building strong relationships with candidates and hiring managers. Currently, I am transitioning into a Human Resource Generalist role to expand my expertise in various HR functions and drive organizational success.

#### EXPERIENCE

## **Talent Acquisition Officer**

#### DawateIslami

December 2022 - Present, Karachi

- Managed full-cycle recruitment for 30 positions throughout the company. Screened resumes and applications to identify suitable candidates, while providing feedback to unsuccessful candidates.
- · Conducted initial phone screenings to assess candidate qualifications, and scheduled on-site interviews to determine hiring decisions.
- · Coordinated and conducted in-person interviews.
- · Conducted reference checks on final candidates.
- · Created and analyzed reports on a daily, bi-monthly, and monthly basis to evaluate task performance.
- · Managed employee onboarding, including document processing, offer letters, and data management using software.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Conducted employee induction sessions to educate them about organizational policies and procedures}.$
- Fostered relationships with new employees and monitored job satisfaction.
- · Reduced hiring time by 25% while ensuring the organization hires only qualified employees.

#### **Human Resource Executive**

#### **PrismPay Solutions**

April 2022 - November 2022, Karachi, Pakistan

- Prepared job descriptions for open positions using job descriptions from previous years and the company's job evaluation form.
- Recruited over 30 new employees, in a span of 3 months, for the company's new division.
- Handled employee concerns and personal matters confidentially and professionally by collecting information, conducting investigations, and making decisions within the company policy.
- Prepared pay slips and new hire documentation for 50+ new employees and conducted new employee orientation for employees in the first year of employment, having a positive impact in retention rates of employees.
- · Managed employee data and attendance records by ensuring 99% accuracy of employee data and attendance records.
- · Posted and maintained 100% unique, weekly content on Twitter, and LinkedIn for the company's social media presence.
- Handled the payroll of over 70+ employees, calculated and distributed salary payments to employees on a monthly basis, and verified that taxes and other deductions accounted for in the payroll process.
- $\cdot$  Managing performance of employees and calculating KPI's with respect to their attendance and their task achieved by weekly, bi-monthly and monthly basis.

## **PROJECTS**

#### Waste Management Issues In Pakistan

University Of Karachi • June 2021 - August 2021

- · Responsible for looking after the project and created content that's more engageable and relevant for the public.
- · Provided solution through 3r's and spread awareness that how to reduce waste in Karachi.

# **EDUCATION**

#### Master's In Human Resource Management

Minor in Accounts · University Of Karachi · Karachi, Paksitan · 2022

#### CERTIFICATIONS

#### **McKinsey Forward Program**

McKinsey And Company • 2023

Mckinsey Forward Learner program which enables to think about a problem from multiple perspective and come to a better solution that would help the customer and business as well.

# **COURSEWORK**

**Human Resources: Payroll** 

Linkedin · 2023

Human Resources: Using Metrics to Drive HR Strategy

Linkedin ⋅ 2023

**Strategic Human Resources** 

Linkedin ⋅ 2023

**Talent Sourcing** 

Linkedin · 2023

HR as a Business Partner

Linkedin · Invalid date

# **SKILLS**

Soft Skills: Active Listener, Communicator, Problem Solver

Software: Excel, Premier Pro